<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Vishnu&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://vishnubraj.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Vishnu&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vishnubraj.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Elastic Search Index, Shards and Replicas</title>
      <link>https://vishnubraj.github.io/post/elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishnubraj.github.io/post/elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>Index, Shards and Replicas An index is automatically created when a document is inserted into the Elastic search. we can define the number shards, while creating the index or it will take default 5 shards It means elastic search will create 5 primary shards that will contain our data
 Every time we index a document, elasticsearch will decide which primary shard is supposed to hold that document and will index it there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vishnubraj.github.io/post/routerswitchcompare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishnubraj.github.io/post/routerswitchcompare/</guid>
      <description>Disadvantages of using Layer 3 switch as a router Doesn&amp;rsquo;t support MPLS and VPN services Doesn&amp;rsquo;t support NAT, firewalling, tunnel, IPSec Size of routing table is small Forwarding is performed by ASIC No QOS support
Advantages of using routers
Non-Ethernet connections (which still do exist) Large routing tables; check the verified scalability document for your favorite Cisco switch — numbers like 8,000, 24,000, or 32,000 prefixes are common Many routing VRFs — campus and datacenter switches don’t need ‘em, at least for common uses NAT, especially with protocol fixups (address in payload situations) Large ACLs without loss of efficiency QoS not tied to 4 or 8 hardware queues (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
